As an artist,
كفنانة،
connection is very important to me.
الروابط ذات أهمية كبيرة بالنسبة لي.
Through my work I'm trying to articulate
أحاول من خلال عملي إظهار
that humans are not separate from nature
أن البشر ليسوا منفصلين عن الطبيعة
and that everything is interconnected.
وأن كل شيء مترابط.
I first went to Antarctica almost 10 years ago,
ذهبت أولا إلى القارة القطبية الجنوبية قبل 10 سنوات،
where I saw my first icebergs.
حيث رأيت أول كتل جليدية متحركة.
I was in awe.
كنت في هلع.
My heart beat fast, my head was dizzy,
قلبي ينبض بسرعة، أصبت بالدوار في رأسي،
trying to comprehend what it was that stood in front of me.
محاولة فهم ما الذي يقف أمامي.
The icebergs around me
كتل الجليد المتحركة حولي
were almost 200 feet out of the water,
كانت بارتفاع 200 قدم تقريبا. فوق الماء.
and I could only help but wonder
ولم أستطع سوى أن أندهش
that this was one snowflake
بأن هذا كان ندفة ثلج
on top of another snowflake,
فوق ندفة ثلج أخرى،
year after year.
عاما بعد عام.
Icebergs are born
تولد كتل الجليد المتحركة
when they calve off of glaciers
حين تنفصل عن المثلجة
or break off of ice shelves.
أو تنفصل عن رفوف الجليد.
Each iceberg has its own individual personality.
كل كتلة جليدية متحركة لها شخصيتها الخاصة.
They have a distinct way
لديها طريقة خاصة
of interacting with their environment
في التفاعل مع محيطها
and their experiences.
وتجاربها.
Some refuse to give up
بعضها يرفض الإستسلام
and hold on to the bitter end,
وتصمد إلى نهاية مريرة،
while others can't take it anymore
في حين لم يعد آخرون يستطيع التحمل
and crumble in a fit of dramatic passion.
فتتفتت في نوبة حماس درامية.
It's easy to think, when you look at an iceberg,
من السهل الإعتقاد، حين ننظر إلى كتلة جليد متحركة،
that they're isolated,
أنها منعزلة،
that they're separate and alone,
أنها منفصلة ووحيدة،
much like we as humans sometimes view ourselves.
أشبه بما نرى عليه أنفسنا نحن البشر أحيانا.
But the reality is far from it.
لكن الواقع بعيد عن ذلك.
As an iceberg melts,
بذوبان كتلة الجليد المتحركة،
I am breathing in
أتنفس
its ancient atmosphere.
هواءها العتيق.
As the iceberg melts,
بذوبان كتلة الجليد،
it is releasing mineral-rich fresh water
تطلق مياها عذبة غنية بالمواد المعدنية
that nourishes many forms of life.
تغذي الكثير من أشكال الحياة.
I approach photographing these icebergs
أنتهج تصوير كتل الجليد المتحركة هذه
as if I'm making portraits of my ancestors,
كأنني ألتقط صورا لأسلافي،
knowing that in these individual moments
مدركة أنه في هذه اللحظات المنفردة
they exist in that way
توجد بتلك الطريقة
and will never exist that way again.
ولن توجد بتلك الطريقة مجددا أبدا.
It is not a death when they melt;
ليس ذوبانها موتا؛
it is not an end,
وليس نهاية،
but a continuation
لكن استمرارية
of their path through the cycle of life.
لمسارها من خلال دورة الحياة.
Some of the ice in the icebergs that I photograph is very young --
بعض الجليد على الكتل الجليدية المتحركة التي أصور في غاية الحداثة --
a couple thousand years old.
بعمر بضعة آلاف سنة.
And some of the ice
وبعض الجليد
is over 100,000 years old.
عمره حوالي 100,000 سنة.
The last pictures I'd like to show you
آخر صورة أود أن أريها لكم
are of an iceberg that I photographed
هي لكتلة جليدية متحركة صورتها
in Qeqetarsuaq, Greenland.
في كيكرتسواتسياك في غرينلاند.
It's a very rare occasion
إنها مناسبة في غاية الندرة
that you get to actually witness
أن تستطيع بالفعل معاينة
an iceberg rolling.
كتلة جليدية متحركة تتدحرج.
So here it is.
إذن ها هو هنا.
You can see on the left side a small boat.
يمكنكم رؤية قارب صغير على اليسار.
That's about a 15-foot boat.
ذلك بارتفاع حوالي 15 قدما.
And I'd like you to pay attention
وأريد منكم الإنتباه
to the shape of the iceberg
إلى شكل الكتلة الجليدية المتحركة
and where it is at the waterline.
وموقعها في الماء.
You can see here, it begins to roll,
يمكنكم رؤية أنها بدأت تتدحرج هنا،
and the boat has moved to the other side, and the man is standing there.
والقارب قد تحرك إلى الجهة الأخرى، والرجل يقف هناك.
This is an average-size Greenlandic iceberg.
هذه كتلة جليدية متحركة بحجم متوسط في غرينلاند.
It's about 120 feet above the water,
إنها بعلو حوالي 120 قدما فوق الماء،
or 40 meters.
أو 40 مترا.
And this video is real time.
وهذا الفيديو تم تصويره مباشرة.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
And just like that,
وبهذه الطريقة،
the iceberg shows you a different side of its personality.
ترينا الكتلة الجليدية المتحركة جانبا مختلفا من شخصيتها.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)